Lena Zellinger

L.Zellinger@sms.ed.ac.uk https://github.com/LenaZellinger https://x.com/lena_zellinger

I am an ELLIS PhD student supervised by Dr. Antonio Vergari, Dr. Nikolay Malkin, and Dr. Vincent Fortuin. I am a member of the APRIL research lab at the University of Edinburgh and the ELPIS research lab at Helmholtz AI and TU Munich. My main research interests include efficient and interpretable neuro-symbolic machine learning as well as tractable uncertainty quantification.

EDUCATION

PhD at the Institute for Adaptive and Neural Computation

2024 - present

University of Edinburgh, School of Informatics

- supervised by Dr. Antonio Vergari and Dr. Nikolay Malkin
- · co-advised by Dr. Vincent Fortuin at Helmholtz Al and TUM through ELLIS

MSc in Data Science 2020 - 2022

University of Vienna, Faculty of Computer Science

- master's thesis: "Gradient Matching for Learning with Noisy Data"
- graduated with honors, overall GPA: 1.18 (1 = best, 5 = worst)
- completed within minimum duration of study as the first graduate of the program

BSc in Statistics 2017 - 2020

University of Vienna, Faculty of Business, Economics and Statistics

- · graduated with honors
- completed within minimum duration of study

RESEARCH & TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant Oct 2022 - Nov 2023

University of Vienna, Research Group Data Mining and Machine Learning

Tutor for Analysis and Advanced AnalysisUniversity of Vienna, Faculty of Business, Economics and Statistics

Oct 2019 - Jan 2021

ACADEMIC HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Best of the Best Award (2022): award given to the top 3 master's graduates of the Faculty of Computer Science Class of Excellence (2018 - 2019): program for top students of the Faculty of Business, Economics and Statistics Performance Scholarship (2019 - 2022): yearly merit-based scholarship awarded by the University of Vienna

PUBLICATIONS

A. Sedova*, **L. Zellinger***, and B. Roth. Learning with noisy labels by adaptive gradient-based outlier removal. ECML PKDD 2023. **L. Zellinger**, A. Stephan, and B. Roth. Counterfactual reasoning with knowledge graph embeddings. EACL 2024. (Oral)

Last updated: Oct 2024

^{*}equal contribution